jobbatical.com 2018-12-30

# Privacy Policy - Jobbatical

Last update: May 4, 2018

We are Jobbatical (Jobbatical OÜ, registry code 12671900, address at Niine Street 11, Tallinn, Republic of Estonia), an Estonian company dedicated in offering online services for employment opportunities via our website [jobbatical.com](https://jobbatical.com/). We provide a marketplace connecting job seekers/employees to employers for short-term jobs. We enable posting and searching of personal profiles, job vacancies and other employment related opportunities. Hereby we determine and explain the purpose of the processing of the data and the persons to whom communication of the data is permitted, the conditions for communicating the data to third persons and your rights concerning further processing of your personal data.

By joining Jobbatical, creating your account and accepting our Terms and Conditions and this Privacy Policy, you are giving us your permission to process your personal data pursuant to conditions of this Privacy Policy. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. In case of any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please kindly contact us [support@jobbatical.com](mailto:support@jobbatical.com).

We process (including collect, store, save, distribute, compile, use, make available to, etc.) personal data submitted by you at the sign up and on your account. We do not collect any personal data about you which is made available outside our platform.

We collect and process the following personal data: name, date of birth, location, work experience, skills, education, contact information, e-mail address and other personal information related to your suitability for a job vacancy. You do not have to provide any other personal data which is not mentioned in our profile list on our website. Please take into account that some of the personal information may be sensitive personal data and therefore we ask you to think twice before you decide to make it available.

We collect and process job seekers` personal data for the purpose of matching up to employers across the globe for short term jobs. Upon your and other job seekers` separate consent we forward data to the employers to enable to decide whether the job seeker is the one they are looking for. For making your profile and personal data available for employers and start active job seeking process please click the relevant button on your profile. Otherwise your information will not be visible to employers.

We use your personal information to create a profile of you. The profile-making process is not an automated decision which results in legal consequences for you or significantly affects the data about you. As a job seeker you agree that we may assess your skills, experiences, current location or other characteristics and express our preferences to the employers. For providing our services we may, at our discretion, evaluate your suitability to a given job vacancy, create opinions and evaluations which we provide to interested employers (pre-moderation) and provide shortlisting services to employers which may relate to further processing of your personal data.

Upon your separate consent we may provide your profile to an employer even if you are not applying for the vacant position and for these purposes you grant us the right to retain your personal data beyond any given job vacancy you have applied for. Please note that you may withdraw your consent at any given time by communicating such request via [support@jobbatical.com](mailto:support@jobbatical.com).

We may help the employers with pre-selection of possible employees during which we may add to your profile some comments on why we feel that you are the best for this position. However, the final decision is always made by the employer. We do not interview you nor do we conduct any background research. All the data you make available on your account shall be available to potential employers as it is provided by you.

We may also use the personal data such as contact details to resolve any service quality issues between us.

If you make your social media profiles available on your Jobbatical account, we assure that we do not store, compile or analyze your social media data, unless you have authorized us to do so. We are not processing your social media data and it is your own responsibility to clarify any social media data misuse or misinterpretation.

Personal data is disclosed only to employers who have joined Jobbatical. Profile and other personal information is not available to the public and it is not allowed to index the data by search engines such as Google.

For the purposes of improving your user experience when using Jobbatical services, we track activities you perform on our website and some of your personal data is disclosed to web analytic, applicant tracking system (ATS) and other services providers. For example, we track your activity in relation to links that you click on our website (including links to third party websites) and we also use email tracking to understand whether you have received our messages.

Web analytic service providers analyze your use of the Jobbatical web platform and services so we could improve and amend the way our website and platform function. Applicant tracking system is a software application that allows an organization to collect and store candidate and job related data and track and monitor the process of candidates through all stages of the hiring process. At the moment of accepting these Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policy, personal data is transferred to following web analytic service and ATS software providers:

 **[Segment.io](http://segment.io/), Inc.**, address at 101 15th St, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA, e-mail address [legal@segment.com](mailto:legal@segment.com), for further information please also see [segment.com/docs/legal/terms](https://segment.com/docs/legal/terms);

 **Mixpanel, Inc.** , address at 405 Howard St, Floor 2, San Francisco, CA 94105, USA, e-mail address [support@mixpanel.com](mailto:support@mixpanel.com), for further information please also see [mixpanel.com/terms](https://mixpanel.com/terms);

 **Workable Software Limited** , (Company No. 08125469) of WeWork, 1 Fore St, London EC2Y 5EJ, email: [support@workable.com](mailto:support@workable.com), for further information please also see [workable.com/terms](https://workable.com/terms);

 **The Rocket Science Group, LLC / MailChimp** , address in Georgia, USA, e-mail address [privacy@mailchimp.com](mailto:privacy@mailchimp.com), for further information please also see [mailchimp.com/legal/terms](https://mailchimp.com/legal/terms);

 **Greenhouse Software, Inc.** , address at 110 Fifth Avenue, 3rd Floor, New York, NY 10011, USA, e-mail address [info@greenhouse.io](mailto:info@greenhouse.io), for further information please also see [greenhouse.io/legal](https://greenhouse.io/legal);

 **Amazon Web Services, Inc.** , address at 1200 12th Avenue South, Suite 1200, Seattle, WA 98144, USA, for contact information please see [aws.amazon.com/contact-us](https://aws.amazon.com/contact-us), for further information please also see [aws.amazon.com](https://aws.amazon.com/);

 **Looker Data Sciences, Inc.** , address 101 Church St, Santa Cruz, CA 95060, USA, e-mail address [privacy@looker.com](mailto:privacy@looker.com), for further information please also see [looker.com/terms](https://looker.com/terms);

 **FullStory, Inc.** , address 120 Ottley Drive NE, Suite 100, Atlanta, GA 30324, USA, e-mail address [privacy@fullstory.com](mailto:privacy@fullstory.com), for further information please also see [www.fullstory.com/legal/privacy](https://fullstory.com/legal/privacy/).

By accepting our Terms and Conditions and this Privacy Policy you therefore also understand and agree that upon disclosing your personal data to web analytic service, ATS software and other service providers, some of your personal data is transferred to and processed outside the European Economic Area. In case of any question about the transfer of your personal data to third parties, please contact our support at [support@jobbatical.com](mailto:support@jobbatical.com).

We will not disclose your personal data to any other third parties or public authorities, except if the person requesting data has a legal basis for doing so pursuant to applicable law.

Only authorized employees of Jobbatical have access to the personal data and they may access the data only for the purpose of resolving issues associated with the use of our services.

Pursuant to applicable law we may transfer, process and store personal data in reputable and sufficient cloud databases that are located outside of Estonia and European Union. We reserve ourselves the right to change the cloud service provider at any time without prior notice.

 **Messages, direct marketing and newsletters**

Normally we use your e-mail address only to send you certain relevant notifications about our services which concern your use of services, including important updates and other changes. Upon your separate consent we may also use your e-mail address to send you our newsletters and special offers, including special offers from our partners and employers which could provide interest to you. You may withdraw your consent to receive such direct marketing e-mails at any given time. If you no longer wish to receive these job suggestions, please click the “Unsubscribe” link in the footer of our e-mail.

Upon sending our notifications about our services and providing you with our newsletters and special offers we track your reaction and activity in relation to our notification and messages. For example, we collect information about when you read our message and whether you also opened any attachment. We only do so to understand which information is important to our users in order to help us determine what type of information should we provide you in the future and what information does not have enough interest.

 **Your rights under Privacy Policy and deletion of your account and personal data**

You may request information about personal data that we process about you (personal data report) and submit requests for correcting any of your incorrect personal data. You may also object to our data processing, if you find that we process your personal data or parts of your personal data in violation of your rights. After you have made your profile public in our database you have the right to limit access of any employer to your personal account and your personal data by using relevant buttons on your account.

Under applicable laws you may withdraw your consent to this Privacy Policy at any given time or object to data processing by us under this Privacy Policy. Doing so may, upon our discretion, result in termination of services without any of our further obligations under Terms and Conditions nor liability for us.

By withdrawing your consent, you are deemed to terminate your account in our platform. You may also submit an individual request to delete your account in which case you are also deemed to withdraw your consent to process your personal data. In these cases, we will contact you within seven (7) days to clarify your actual intent and once this is confirmed we will delete your personal data and account permanently latest within thirty (30) days. Provided that within the thirty (30) day period you submit us a request for your information, we will send the information to your contacts within a reasonable period in CVS format.

For exercising your rights under this paragraph please contact us with any of your requests at [support@jobbatical.com](mailto:support@jobbatical.com)

If case you feel that we have violated your privacy rights you may also apply to an appropriate data protection authority for remedy of your rights.

 **Cookies**

As you browse [jobbatical.com](https://jobbatical.com/) website we may place various temporary and permanent cookies, including third party cookies, on your computer, and use similar technologies, in order to understand your interests based on your (anonymous) online activities, and thus to tailor more relevant ads to you. Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive by a website. Cookies help us monitor and improve the functionality and usage of our web site. We use functionality, session, advertising and analytics cookies.

You can delete or block cookies through your browser settings at any time. However, some cookies might be necessary for the functionality of the platform or service. Therefore, you understand that when blocking or deleting the cookies some features of the service might not function correctly. For more general information about cookies please see [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

 **Data Protection Officer**

Our Data Protection Officer responsible for our privacy related obligations is attorney-at-law Tambet Toomela, contact information: telephone +[372 622 9990](tel:3726229990), e-mail [tambet.toomela@eversheds-sutherland.ee ](mailto:tambet.toomela@eversheds-sutherland.ee)
